If you could go back to the city of Jerusalem
in Bible times, the biggest thing you'd
如果你能回到圣经时代的耶路撒冷城，你会看到的最大的东西
see, is the temple.
就是圣殿。
This beautiful building was designed by King
David and built by King Solomon; and
这座美丽的建筑由大卫王设计，所罗门王建造；
they believed it was the home of the God of
the universe.
他们相信这是宇宙之神的家。
Wait, I thought God's home was in heaven.
等等，我以为神的家在天堂。
Well, the whole point of this earthly temple,
is that it's the place that overlaps with
嗯，这座地上圣殿的全部意义在于，它是与
God's heavenly home.
神天家重合的地方。
The temple is where God lives and rules all creation as king.
圣殿是上帝居住的地方，他以君王统治所有受造之物。
That's cool.
这很酷。
But even Solomon who built the temple didn’t
believe that his temple
但即使是建造圣殿的所罗门也不相信他的圣殿
could contain the God of the universe.
能容纳宇宙之神。
Right?
对么？
Yeah, the building was just a symbol, that pointed to the fact that all creation is God's temple
是的，这座建筑只是一个象征，表明所有受造物都是神的殿
temple.
圣殿。
And that is actually what the first page of
the Bible, Genesis, is all about.
这实际上就是圣经的开始，创世记的内容。
Really?
真的吗？
It says that creation is God's temple?
它说创造物是上帝的圣殿？
Well, it doesn't need to say it; the whole story shows it.
好吧，这不需要说； 整个故事都说明了这一点。
God creates an ordered world out of a dark wasteland
上帝通过连续 7 天的讲话，从一片黑暗的荒地中创造出一个有序的世界
by speaking in series of seven days.
Then on the seventh day, God's presence fills creation as he
然后在第七天，当上帝开始休息时，
takes up his rest and rule.
祂的同在充满了受造之物
Similarly, the tabernacle–and later the temple–were built and dedicated in a series
同样，会幕——以及后来的圣殿——是在
of seven speeches and seven days
一系列七次演讲和七日
after which the priest or king could rest and rule in God’s presence.
之后建造和奉献的，之后祭司或国王可以在上帝的面前安息和统治。
Ah, so all of creation is where God intends to dwell.
啊，所以所有的受造之物都是上帝打算居住的地方。
It's like his temple.
就像他的殿。
Exactly.
正是如此。
Now, Turn the page to Genesis 2, and we get
another portrait of creation.
现在，到创世记 2 章，我们看到了另一幅关于创造的画像。
...This one focuses in on the land, and in
the center of the land is a region called
...这个重点是土地，在土地的中心是一个叫做
"Eden", which in Hebrew means "delight".
“伊甸园”的区域，在希伯来语中是“喜悦”的意思。
And in the middle of "Delight", God plants a garden in which God and humanity live together
在“喜悦”中间，上帝放置了一个上帝和人类共同生活的花园
together.
And that's why the temple was modeled afterthe garden
这就是为什么这座寺庙以花园为蓝本。
Filled with imagery of gold and flowers, the Menorah symbolized the tree of life.
充满了黄金和花朵的意象，烛台象征着生命之树。
It's the place where God dwells with his people.
这是上帝与他的子民同住的地方。
Oh, Got it!
哦，明白了！
And check this out.
看看这个。
In the temple, the Israelite priests and Levites were to "to work
在圣殿里，以色列的祭司和利未人要
and to keep" the temple in God's presence.
在神的面前“建造并保守”圣殿。
This is exactly the job description given to humanity in the garden of Eden.
这正是伊甸园中人类被给予的工作。
So these humans were the first priests.
所以这些人类是第一批祭司。
But instead of ruling with God, they wanted to rule on their own terms, and they're
但他们不想与上帝一起统治，而是想按照自己的方式统治，他们被
exiled from the garden-temple.
逐出花园圣殿。
And, like Adam and Eve, Israel's leaders also wanted to rule on their own terms and
而且，像亚当和夏娃一样，以色列的领导人也想按照自己的方式统治，
they too were exiled.
他们也被流放。
The Temple was destroyed, and this left them wondering, did God give up on Israel?
圣殿被毁了，这让他们思考，上帝是否放弃了以色列？
Will God bring about a new creation?
上帝会带来新的创造吗？
Well, the biblical prophets anticipated the day when God would create a new temple, with
好吧，圣经的先知们预见到上帝会创造一个新的圣殿，
a new priesthood; that's when God's presence would fill all of creation.
与新的祭司的那一天； 那时上帝的同在会充满所有的受造物。
And when the Israelites returned to the land, they did rebuild the temple.
当以色列人返回这片土地时，他们确实重建了圣殿。
But that temple didn't turn out the way the prophets hoped.
但那座圣殿并没有像先知们所希望的那样发展。
In fact, later Israelite prophets said that this temple was hopelessly
事实上，后来的以色列先知说这座圣殿已经无可救药地
corrupt.
败坏了。
So they're still waiting, for the ultimate temple.
所以他们仍在等待，最终的殿。
And here we come to the story of Jesus.
在这里，我们来到耶稣的故事。
He said that through him God's presenceand
他说，通过他，上帝的同在和
rule was coming to our world in a new way.
统治以一种新的方式来到我们的世界。
And presented himself as a new kind of priest.
并将自己展示为一种新型的祭司。
But Jesus wasn't a priest, and he didn't work in the Temple.
但耶稣不是祭司，他也没有在圣殿工作。
Right; Jesus said that God's presence, his
rest and rule, was filling the world through
对; 耶稣说上帝的同在，他的
安息和统治，正在通过
his own life, death, and resurrection.
他自己的生、死和复活充满世界。
Jesus was claiming that he was the true temple.
耶稣声称他是真正的圣殿。
And this new temple would expand out to include all of creation.
这座新的圣殿会扩展到包括所有的创造。
That is a really big claim!
这是一个非常大胆的宣告！
And it got bigger!
还不止这些！
After his resurrection, Jesus said that God's
presence would come
耶稣复活后说，上帝的同在
to dwell in and among his followers, so that
they could become mini-temples.
会在他的追随者里面和中间，使他们成为小型的圣殿。
Communities of people where God rests and rules.
上帝安息和统治的人们的社区。
Exactly.
确切地。
This is the Bible’s vision of the church,
which is described as a temple.
这是圣经对教会的异象，
教会被描述为圣殿。
Not a building, but people.
不是建筑物，而是人。
Like when Peter says "you all are living
stones built up as a temple for God's Spirit to dwell".
就像彼得说: 你们来到主面前，也就像活石，被建造成为灵宫，
作圣洁的祭司，藉着耶稣基督奉献神所悦纳的灵祭。
to dwell".
So at the end of the biblical story, do we
ever get a new physical temple?
所以在圣经故事的结尾，我们有
没有得到一座新的实体的圣殿？
Well, not exactly.
嗯，不完全是。
What we see is a renewed cosmic temple, just
like in Genesis one.
我们看到的是一个更新的宇宙圣殿，
就像创世记一章一样。
And this new creation doesn't need a building
because through Jesus, all creation is
而这个新创造不需要建筑，
因为通过耶稣，所有的受造之物
now the place where God rests and rules the
world with his people.
现在都是上帝与他的子民一起安息和统治世界的地方。